earthcam.com 2019-05-21

# EarthCam - Webcam Network

EarthCam - Privacy Policy

EarthCam's policy is to respect and protect the privacy of our users. EarthCam takes your privacy concerns seriously and firmly supports protecting your privacy online. EarthCam will never deliberately reveal private information about our users to any third party without first receiving that user's consent. EarthCam will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone. Please read through this policy statement to understand our practices regarding privacy and learn how we use the information collected from you. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our websites. 

EarthCam collects information that personally identifies you and other personal information about you or users whose information you provide to us to authenticate users and to send notifications to those users relating to EarthCam ("Personal Information"). We do this when you submit a camera site to EarthCam, sign up for EarthCam's free newsletter, sign up for EarthCam's services, post an image to the Hall of Fame, post an image to Facebook or Twitter, and send postcards or whenever you enter an EarthCam sweepstakes or other EarthCam promotion. The user's contact information is used to allow the user to utilize EarthCam features, contact the user when necessary, and advise them about new services, products, and/or software upgrades. The user's Facebook and Twitter account information will only be utilized to post an image or video to the user's account as requested by the user. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings – see the Choice / Opt-Out section below. If EarthCam intends to disclose personal information in some restricted situation, this is specifically explained to you when we collect the information in the rules of sweepstakes or other promotions. 

Personal Information may include: 

  * your name, phone number or other contact details, and the company you work for;
  * your username, password and email when you register for an account to use our services;
  * the information you provide us when you create your account to use any of our services;
  * information about other individuals when you add users through the use of our services and the capacity in which they may use our services;
  * credit card or other financial account information in connection with your order to purchase products and/or services;
  * any information that you upload to the website and/or input into your account; and
  * any other information you may provide to us voluntarily through your use of our websites and services.

The decision to provide this information is optional. However, if you choose not to provide the requested information, you may not be able to use some or all of the features of our websites and/or services. Where this is the case, we will make this clear at the point we ask you to provide the information. 

We automatically collect information regarding the actions you take on our websites and when using our services. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), this information is considered personal information under applicable data protection laws. Usage data helps us understand trends in our users' needs so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor our services and/or advertisements. We may share usage data about our users with third parties for various purposes, including to help us better understand our customers' needs and improve our services. 

When you use our websites and/or services, some examples of the usage data we may collect could include: 

  * the type of Web browser you use;
  * your operating system;
  * your web request;
  * your Internet Service Provider;
  * your IP address;
  * referring/exit pages and URLs;
  * the pages you view and how you interact with links within our services;
  * comments and other content you post via our services;
  * the fact that you have posted comments;
  * the time and duration of your visits to our websites and/or use of our services; and
  * other such information relating to your devices, and your activity on our websites and/or services.

We may store such usage data itself and/or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by EarthCam agents or service providers. We may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to our websites or users of our services, the number of visitors to each page of our websites, etc. We use this information to help us understand how people use our websites and services, and to enhance our websites and services. Our mobile applications may collect certain additional information automatically, including, but not limited to, the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device's unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, available storage space, connection type (e.g. WiFi vs. cellular), and information about the way you use the applications. We may also use GPS technology (or other similar technology) to determine your current location. If you do not want us to have your location information, you should turn off the location services for the mobile applications located in your account settings or in your mobile phone settings and/or within the mobile applications. 

Unique identifiers are collected for use as account numbers in our record system. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor the user's experience at our websites and in displaying the content according to their preferences. 

EarthCam may share information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. We refer to our users as an entirety, not as individuals. For example, we will compare EarthCam's audience of females vs. males with the use of variables such as x and y. 

Our websites and services include social media features, such as sharing images / videos to Facebook and Twitter. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. The social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. 

EarthCam uses cookies to keep track of your custom created EarthCam account and its data. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our websites. EarthCam also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, EarthCam cookie information and the page you requested. We use your IP address to help identify you, generate our statistic logs, and to count the traffic statistics for our websites. 

EarthCam uses cookies to store users' preferences and to record session information, for purposes including ensuring that users are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising, and web page content based on browser type and user profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our websites. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set (each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences). However, you must enable cookies from EarthCam.com, MyEarthCam.com, EarthCam.net, WorkZoneCam.com, and WebCamStore.com in order to use most functions on the websites. Please note that EarthCam allows third party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the EarthCam Privacy Policy. 

Our websites contains links to sites. You could be directed to other websites that are outside of our services and control. EarthCam is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. You are responsible for voluntarily disclosing personal information online. This information is accessible to the public and can be collected and used by others. Keep in mind that when you visit a site, it may be collecting information about you without your knowledge. You should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Remember to be responsible and safe when online. 

Our websites may, at times, makes blogs, chat rooms, journals and web logs, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the user. 

The websites gives users the option for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our services: 

1\. At the bottom of all EarthCam newsletters and advisory notices / promotions regarding new services, products and/or software upgrades, a user can elect to unsubscribe. 

EarthCam provides users with the ability to report a violation they find on our websites by filling out and submitting the EarthCam Contact Us form. 

Users who have submitted their camera for inclusion in the EarthCam database can change and/or modify the information they have previously provided to EarthCam by sending an email documenting the necessary changes they wish to make; and EarthCam will make its best efforts to update this information within 72 hours. 

Users with a My EarthCam or Control Center account can change and/or modify the information they have previously provided by logging in to their account and editing their information. User can simply make all their changes they want and then click on the Submit or Save button. The new information is updated instantaneously. 

Ads appearing on our websites may be delivered to users by EarthCam or one of our advertising partners (<https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>). Our advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by EarthCam and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

EarthCam accounts are secured by user-created passwords. EarthCam takes precautions to insure that account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect account information that is stored within our database and we restrict access to account information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of account information. 

Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of acount information at any time. 

Your Personal Information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective). Specifically, our websites and services are hosted in the United States and our third-party service providers operate around the world. 

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

If you are a visitor from the EEA, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the Personal Information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

However, we will normally collect Personal Information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the Personal Information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect Personal Information from you or may otherwise need the Personal Information to protect your vital interests or those of another person. 

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your Personal Information, or for more details on our legitimate interests, please contact us using the EarthCam Contact Us form.. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or where we have an ongoing business need to do so (for example, to comply with applicable, legal, tax, or accounting requirements). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your Personal Information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your Personal Information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

Upon request, EarthCam will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your Personal Information. You can always review, correct, delete, or update your Personal Information by changing the relevant settings in your account or by emailing us. We will make best efforts to respond to your request within 72 hours. 

You can opt out of receiving certain emails by changing notification settings on our websites, our applications, and/or services, by clicking the unsubscribe link provided in an email, or by emailing us. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us using the EarthCam Contact Us form. 

If you are a visitor from the EEA, you have the following data protection rights: 

  * If you wish to access your Personal Information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the EarthCam Contact Us form. If you wish to correct, update, or request deletion of your personal information, you can always do so by changing the relevant settings in your account or by emailing us.
  * In addition, if you are a resident of the EEA, you can object to processing of your Personal Information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the EarthCam Contact Us form.
  * You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the "unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link in the marketing e-mails we send you. To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us using the EarthCam Contact Us form.
  * Similarly, if we have collected and process your Personal Information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your Personal Information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. (Contact details for data protection authorities in the EEA, Switzerland and certain other countries (including the US) are available online.)

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights promptly. 

Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, EarthCam will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by EarthCam, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) enforce the EarthCam Terms of Service or to protect our rights; or (3) protect the safety of members of the public and users of our websites and/or services. EarthCam reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of EarthCam or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest. 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of our websites, or your dealings with Earthcam, you can send an email or write to us: 

EarthCam, Inc.  
650 East Crescent Avenue  
Upper Saddle River, NJ 07458  

Please check this page periodically, for we reserve the right to make changes to this policy at our discretion at any time.
